Finding Aid for the Lawrence Clark Powell Papers LSC.0229
UCLA Library Special Collections
- California Library Association Records
  - Tickler File
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. (Box 35)
    - Publications Committee. (Box 35)
    - Regional Cooperation, CLA Committee on. (Box 35)
    - School Library Association. (Box 35)
    - School Library Consultant Service. (Box 35)
    - Southern District Meeting. (Box 35)
    - State Meeting, 1950. (Box 35)
    - CLA Conference,: Post-Mortem., June 21-24 (Box 35)
    - Official State Ballot. (Box 35)
    - Sections: Boys & Girls, Junior Members, Municipal Libraries
      - Separate files: Curls & Trustees. (Box 35)
    - Theatre Library Association. (Box 36, Folder T-Y and Miscellaneous)
    - Trustees Section. (Box 36)
    - Yelland, Mrs. W.R. (Box 36)
      See also: Budget & Finance.
    - Yelland Letters. (Box 36)
    - Yosemite District Meeting. (Box 36)
    - California Library Association Miscellaneous, 1944-1948. (Box 36)
    - CLA Development Committee Circulars. (Box 36, Othertype Three-Ring Binder)
- Zamorano Club
  - 1949-June 1955. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - 1955 and 1956. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - 1956 and 1957. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - 1958-. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Future Meetings. (Box 37, Folder 5)
- Articles About Lawrence Clark Powell
  - Jackson, John B. Personalities in UCLA History, no.2: Lawrence Clark Powell. In The UCLA Magazine (vol.19, no.9), December 1944. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    See Publications file, The Library and the Alumni, The UCLA Magazine (vol.19, no.9) December 1944.
  - Marshall, Bertah. Our Frontispiece, Lawrence Clark Powell. In Bulletin of Bibliography (vol.20, no.10), January-April 1953. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Harlow, Neal. Living Librarians IX: Lawrence Clark Powell. In ALA Bulletin, November 1954. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Dobie, J. Frank. A librarian and books. In San Antonio Sunday Light, December 19, 1954. (Box 38, Folder 3a)
  - Harlow, Neal. Tribute to a Librarian. In The UCLA Alumni Magazine (vol.30, no.8), April 1955. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Ellsworth, Ralph E. Souse Me in Literature. In Bookman's Briefcase (no.14/15), May-June 1959. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark [Bibliographical Notice]. Current Biography (vol.21, no.6), June 1960. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Dillon, Richard H. Lawrence Clark Powell; Renaissance man in a flip-top age. In Library Journal (vol.90, no.22), December 15, 1965. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Speech delivered by Edwin Castagna, Vice President, ALA,..., February 22, 1964. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Clark Library Celebration. In The UCLA Magazine (vol.23, no.9), May 1949. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - UCLA Librarian Home from England. In The UCLA Alumni Magazine (vol.27, no.2), October 1951. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - The School of Librarianship is pleased to announce that..... (Box 38, Folder 11)
    Dr. Lawrence Clark Powell,...Ex Libris, University of Denver Libraries (no.36) April 1, 1961.
  - Ezell, Kathryn C. Into the Mainstream. In Staff News, Published by the Staff Association of the Chicago Public Library (Third Series: vol.2, no.6), October 1961. (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - The Book Barons. Broadcast no.4039--U.E. 1762. Sunday, Columbia Broadcasting System. KNX, Los Angeles, 9:30 A.M.; KCBS, San Francisco, 9:15 A.M. University Explorer script about rare books., April 2, 1961. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - The Great Paper Chase [Issac Foot Collection]. Time (vol.79, no.14), April 6, 1962. (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1951-. (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1950-. (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Press Releases. (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Reviews of Lawrence Clark Powell's works. (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Schuman, Marilyn. Dr. Lawrence Clark Powell puts shoe on other foot. In Colorado Academic Library, (vol.6, no.2)., Spring 1970.; (p.12) (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Meier, Steve. Library's dedication marked by unconventional address. In The Occidental, (vol.75 no.13)., January 26, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    For tape of speech see box 71: Dedication...
    See box 80 for published ed. Remarks...
  - Lawrence Clark Powell. UCLA Alumni Association, Occasional Paper no.3. (with this Occasional Papers no.1 & 2)., Fall-Winter, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 21)
- Memorabilia
  - Early Years
    - Early Books Belonging to Lawrence Clark Powell. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Marengo Literary Leader (vol.1, no.1-13), [Grammar School Paper, South Pasadena, California]., October 7, 1917-June 20, 1920 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - South Pasadena High School
    - South Pasadena High School Year Books, 1921-22. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - South Pasadena High School Year Books, 1923-24. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Diploma from South Pasadena High School, June 19, 1924. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Occidental College
    - Drama at Occidental College, 1927-1929. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Phi Gamma Delta and the Owl and Key Society, 1925-1929. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Diploma and Commencement Program from Occidental College, June 1929. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Student handbooks, 1926-.; (4 vol.) (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - The La Encina, published by the Junior Class of Occidental College, Los Angeles, 1926. (Box 40)
      - La Encina, The Annual of Occidental College, published by the Associated Students of Occidental College (vol.21), 1927. (Box 40)
      - La Encina, Being the Twenty Second Annual published by the Associated Students, 1928. (Box 40)
      - La Encina, published by the Associated Students of Occidental College (vol.23), 1929. (Box 40)
  - Advanced and Honorary Degrees
    - Certificates from Dijon, 1930-1936. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Certificate from the School fo Librarianship, University of California, Berkeley, May 22, 1937. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Honorary Degree of Doctor of Letters conferred by Occidental College, June 12, 1955. (Box 41, Folder 3)
      Includes Program, bulletins, correspondence, newspaper clipping, citation, a photograph, etc.
    - Citation for the Honorary Degree of Doctor of Humane Letters conferred by Carnegie Institute of Technology at the Dedication of the Hunt Library., October 10, 1961. (Box 41, Folder 4)
      (See also box 130)
    - Honorary Degree of Doctor of Humane Letters conferred by Juniata College, October 7, 1963. (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Certificate of membership in Phi Beta Kappa, awarded, April 7, 1965. (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Convocation in honor of held, July 11, 1966. (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Honorary Degree of Doctor of Humane Letters, conferred by Lycoming College, Williamsport, Pennsylvania., May 9, 1968. (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Honorary Degree of Doctor of Humanities conferred by the University of Arizona, Tucson., May 29, 1971. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Photograph Albums and Scrapbooks
    For other scrapbooks see University History Vertical File, and the records of the University Library in the University Archives.
    - Dedication of the Hunt Library and the Rachel McMasters Miller Hunt Botanical Library. Carnegie Institute of Technology. Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania., October 10, 1961. (Box 42)
    - Fifth Air Force Library Workshop. Tokyo, Japan., April 19-22, 1960. (Box 42)
  - Dijon Memorabilia
    - Programs, exhibits and invitations, etc. (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Announcements, citations, etc. (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Photographs
    - 1914-1924. (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Portraits of LCP. (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Group photos, speaking engagements, library functions. (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Family pictures. (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 43, Folder 5)
- Publications File
  This file includes all publications that are not filed under individual headings, such as A Passion for Books.
  Publications are filed by year in alphabetical order by title, except book reviews, which are filed by the author's last name at at the end of each year.
  Unless otherwise indicated all of the titles are by Lawrence Clark Powell.
  See also boxes 23-25 (1929-1959)
  - 1930-1944
    - D.H. Lawrence: [Controversy over D.H. Lawrence in The Saturday Review of Literature with Louis Untermeyer and Arthur Colton], (Lawrence Clark Powell's first nationally published writing)., 1930. (Box 44)
    - Memories. In The Phi Gamma Delta. Cedar Rapids, Iowa, []., 1931 (Box 44)
    - Harry Ward Ritchie: Printer. In The Phi Gamma Delta. Cedar Rapids, Iowa, October 1931. (Box 44)
    - Abandons Bitters for Buskin. In Phi Gamma Delta, May 1934. (Box 44)
    - Carey McWilliams: an Estimate. In Apéritif, 1935. (Box 44)
    - La Machine à Ecrire. In Apéritif, 1935. (Box 44)
    - Thomas Beck in Hollywood. In Phi Gamma Delta. Cedar Rapids, Iowa, March 1935. (Box 44)
    - Ex Libris Omega Dappa. In Revista Occidental, 1936. (Box 44)
    - Ward Ritchie: Printer. In Occidental College Founder's Day Exhibition, 1936. (Box 44)
    - D.H. Lawrence. Phoenix. In Los Angeles Saturday Night, December 12, 1936. (Box 44)
    - John (Ernst) Steinbeck. A Checklist. In Publishers' Weekly, April 17, 1937. (Box 44)
    - The Manuscripts of D.H. Lawrence, a Descriptive Catalog. Los Angeles Public Library, Compiled by Lawrence Clark Powell with a foreword by Aldous Huxley., 1937. (Box 44)
    - Goncourt Journals. In Los Angeles Times, (Book Review)., October 3, 1937 (Box 44)
    - Comme-çi, Comme-ça. In Los Angeles Saturday Night, February 26, 1938. (Box 44)
    - On Collecting John Steinbeck. In Book Collectors' Packet, July 1938. (Box 44)
    - Who Is B. Traven? New Masses, August 2, 1938. (Box 44)
    - C.F. MacIntyre. Wilson Bulletin, March 1939. (Box 44)
    - H. Clark Powell, Memoirs of his life and a bibliography of his writings. Los Angeles: Ward Ritchie Press, 1900-1938. 1939. (Box 44)
    - John Steinbeck. Black and White, June 1939. (Box 44)
    - Oktoberlied: Occidental Acquires a Bas-relief by a Distinguished Son. In Occidental Alumnus, October, 1939. (Box 44)
    - Problem of Rare Books in the College and University Library. In Library Journal, April 1, 1939. (Box 44)
    - Tom Wolfe's First Opus. In Publishers' Weekly, November 25, 1939. (Box 44)
    - [Forward to] The Wrath of John Steinbeck, by Robert Bennett. Los Angeles: Albertson Press, 1939. (Box 44)
    - D.H. Lawrence and His Critics. A Chronological Excursion in Bio-bibliography. In Colophon, new graphic series, February 1940. (Box 44)
    - Libraries and War... Newsnotes from College and University Libraries. In California Library Association Bulletin., December 1940. (Box 44)
    - Book Exhibits at the UCLA Library. In UCLA Magazine, December 1941. (Box 44)
    - Poetry. On the Record [published by the Gateway to Music, Los Angeles] (vol.3, no.6), June 1941. (Box 44)
    - The Rounce & Coffin Club. Exhibition of Western Books, Compiled by Lawrence Clark Powell. Stanford University Press, 1941. 1941. (Box 44)
    - Ten Years (almost) of Rounce & Coffin-ism. Los Angeles, Rounce & Coffin Club, 1941. (Box 44)
    - An Unpublished Mark Twain Letter. Reprinted from American Literature, January 1942. (Box 44)
    - Academic Library Notes. In California Library Association Bulletin, June 1943. (Box 44)
    - I Read What I like. In Wilson Library Bulletin, October, 1943. (Box 44)
    - The Writings of Aldous Huxley, 1916-1943; an Exhibition of the Collection of Jacob I. Zeitlin at the Library of the University of California, Edited and with an introduction by Lawrence Clark Powell. Los Angeles, July 1 to August 15, 1943. 1943. (Box 44)
    - Ernest Marchand. Frank Norris: a Study. In Pacific Historical Review, [Book Review]., September 1943 (Box 44)
    - The Library and the Alumni. In UCLA Magazine, December 1944. (Box 44)
    - Travel Notes from the Shipping Room. In Wilson Library Bulletin, May 1944. (Box 44)
    - Fremont Rider. The Scholar and the Future of the Research Library. In Modern Language Forum, [Book Review]., December 1944 (Box 44)
    - Edward Rowland Sill. Around the Horn: a Journal. In Pacific Historical Review, a reprint from, [Book Review]., September 1944 (Box 44)
  - 1945-1948
    - An Almanac for Librarians. In Wilson Library Bulletin, June 1945. (Box 45)
    - [Forward to] Know Your Library (1st edition). University of California, Los Angeles, 1945. (Box 45)
    - A Great American Nature Writer: Donald Culross Peatie. In Phi Gamma Delta, June 1945. (Box 45)
    - The Librarian's Occasional Letter to the Faculty. University of California, Los Angeles. [no.1 & 2:; no.3 & 4:; no.5:; no.6:; no.7: ]., 1945 1946 1947 1948 1950 (Box 45)
    - We Moderns. In SCOP, Summer 1945. (Box 45)
    - We Moderns. In Wilson Library Bulletin, November 1945. (Box 45)
    - We Moderns. [Excerpts from]. Ben Abramson's Argus Book Shop Catalogue, no.20., 1945 (Box 45)
    - [Contributions to] Acquisitive Notes. Edited by Robert Vosper (no.1 & 3), 1946. (Box 45)
    - [Forward to] Know Your Library (2nd edition). University of California, Los Angeles, 1946. (Box 45)
    - A Tribute to Benjamin F. Stelter. In Occidental Alumnus, December 1946. (Box 45)
    - A University Librarian Takes Pen in Hand. In Library Journal, April 1, 1946. (Box 45)
    - Ward Ritchie: Printer. Book Collector's Packet 4, no.9-10., 1946 (Box 45)
    - Academic Library Notes. In California Library Bulletin, December 1947. (Box 45)
    - Biographical Note on Thomas Perry Stricker. In Elizabeth's Merlin, by Anthony Hillyer. Los Angeles, 1947. (Box 45)
    - Book Notes. In Hoja Volante (no.14), February 1947. (Box 45)
    - Confessions of a Reconstructed Westerner. In Hoja Volante, August 1947. (Box 45)
    - From the Librarian. In UCLA Librarian, Bi-weekly Bulletin for the Staff, October 16, 1947-June 18, 1954. (Box 45)
    - I am an Escapist. In Hoja Volante, May 1947. (Box 45)
    - Leaves of Whitman. In Hoja Volante, November 1947. (Box 45)
    - Librarians as Readers of Books. In Pacific Northwest Library Association Quarterly, September 1947. (Box 45)
    - The Librarian's Occasional Letter to the Faculty (no.5), 1947. (Box 45)
    - Thomas C. Lancey, Chronicler of '46. In Pacific Historical Review, February 1947. (Box 45)
    - [Foreword to] Know Your Library. University of California, Los Angeles. Third Edition, 1947. (Box 45)
    - Van Wyck Brooks. The Times of Melville and Whitman. In Los Angeles Daily News, Book Section, (Book Review)., November 29, 1947 (Box 45)
    - G.P. Putnam. Death Valley and its Country. In Pacific Historical Review, February 1947. (Box 45)
    - Academic Library Notes. In California Library Bulletin, March-December 1948. (Box 45)
    - The Chief Librarian: Bookman or Administrator? Strechert-Hafner Book News, October 1948. (Box 45)
    - [Contributions to] Acquisitive Notes (no.6). Edited by Robert Vosper, 1948. (Box 45)
    - The Enjoyment of Joyce. In Hoja Volante, May 1948. (Box 45)
    - [Foreword to] Know Your Library (4th edition). University of California, Los Angeles, 1948. (Box 45)
    - From the Librarian. In UCLA Librarian, Bi-weekly Bulletin for the Staff (vol.1, no.7-18,20-22,24,26; vol.2, no.1-6), January 8, 1948-December 23, 1948. (Box 45)
    - Giacomo Girolamo Casanova, Chevalier de Seingalt, 1726-1798. Pasadena: The Ampersand Press, 1948. (Box 45)
    - Librarians as Readers of Books. [pamphlet] Seattle: The Dogwood Press, 1948. (Box 45)
    - The Librarian's Occasional Letter to the Faculty (no.6), 1948. (Box 45)
    - Lines on Lawrence. In Hoja Volante, November 1948. (Box 45)
    - Rabelaisian Notes. In Hoja Volante, February 1948. (Box 45)
    - San Joaquin Vision. [Reprint from the] California Library Bulletin, June 1948. (Box 45)
    - San Joaquin Vision. In Wilson Library Bulletin, October 1948. (Box 45)
    - Ward Ritchie, Printer. In The Western Printer and Lithographer, August 1948. (Box 45)
  - 1949-1951
    - Acknowledgments, Handlist of an Exhibition of Great American Historical Documents, Manuscripts & Books. University of California, Los Angeles., 1949. (Box 46)
    - [Contributions to] Acquisitive Notes (no.8-9). Edited by Robert Vosper, 1949. (Box 46)
    - Books and People and the Earth on Which We Live. In Pacific Northwest Library Association Quarterly, October 1949. (Box 46)
    - The Chief Librarian: Bookman or Administrator? Publishers' Circular and Bookseller's Record. [London], March 26, 1949. (Box 46)
    - The Chief Librarian: Bookman or Administrator? Antiquarian Bookman, January 8, 1949. (Box 46)
    - [Foreword to] Know Your Library (5th edition). University of California, Los Angeles, 1949. (Box 46)
    - From the Librarian. In UCLA Librarian, Bi-weekly Bulletin for the Staff (vol.2, no.7-9,22-26; vol.3, no.1,3-6)., January 6, 1949-December 22, 1949. (Box 46)
    - Glory of Life. In Hoja Volante, August 1949. (Box 46)
    - In It Together. In Antiquarian Bookman, July 9, 1949. (Box 46)
    - [A Note on Lawrence Durrell in] A Landmark Gone, by Lawrence Durrell. Los Angeles, 1949. (Box 46)
    - My Melville. In Hoja Volante, February 1949. (Box 46)
    - Nine by Nine. In Hoja Volante, May 1949. (Box 46)
    - Rare Books in the University Library: Policy and Administration and Rare Book Code. In College and Research Libraries, July 1949. (Box 46)
    - The Time, the Place and the Book. In Hoja Volante, November 1949. (Box 46)
    - The UCLA Library. Age: Thirty Years. In UCLA Magazine, January 1949. (Box 46)
    - Bookman in Britain. In Hoja Volante, November 1950. (Box 46)
    - Books and People and the Earth on Which We Live. In Wilson Library Bulletin, February 1950. (Box 46)
    - Books on the Land. In California Library Bulletin, March 1950. (Box 46)
    - Books on the Land. In Hoja Volante, May 1950. (Box 46)
    - Bookseller and Librarian. An Address Given Before the Southern California Chapter of the Antiquarian Booksellers' Association of America, Antiquarian Booksellers' Association News Letter. [London], May 11th, 1949. Spring 1950. (Box 46)
    - A California Bookman Abroad. California Librarian, December 1950. (Box 46)
    - From the Librarian. In UCLA Librarian, Bi-weekly Bulletin for the Staff (vol.3, no.7-19), January 5-June 22, 1950. (Box 46)
    - From Private Collection to Public Institution: the William Andrews Clark Memorial Library. In Library Quarterly, April 1950. (Box 46)
    - Invitation from CLA. Bulletin of the School Library Association of California, May 1950. (Box 46)
    - [Foreword to] Know Your Library (6th edition). University of California, Los Angeles, 1950. (Box 46)
    - The Librarian's Occasional Letter to the Faculty (no.7), 1950. (Box 46)
    - Personal Landscape. In Hoja Volante, August 1950. (Box 46)
    - Ripeness is All. In Hoja Volante, February 1950. (Box 46)
    - A Source of Power and Beauty. [Remarks at the Dedication of the Montana State College Library, Bozeman, ]. Montana Collegian, May 10, 1950 June 1950. (Box 46)
    - [Foreword to] Staff Handbook (revised edition). UCLA Library Staff Association, 1950. (Box 46)
    - Address [at a meeting of the National Book League, London, November 1950]. Antiquarian Bookman, March 1951. (Box 46)
    - The Association. In Antiquarian Booksellers' Association News Letter, July 1951. (Box 46)
    - Book Collectors and California Libraries. In Antiquarian Bookman, June 30, 1951. (Box 46)
    - Book Hunter in Britain. [Reprinted from] California Librarian, March 1951.; (2 copies) (Box 46)
    - Book Thoughts from Abroad. [Reprinted from] California Librarian, June 1951. (Box 46)
    - Book Thoughts from Oxford. In Book Club of California Quarterly News Letter, Winter 1951. (Box 46)
    - Books on the Wing. In A Catalogue of English Books Printed Prior to 1701 (Catalogue 31), [Book Dealer's Catalogue]., 1951 (Box 46)
    - Bruin Librarian Brings Home the Books. In UCLA Alumni Magazine, December 1951. (Box 46)
    - The Free Flow of Books. [Reprinted from] Library Journal, October 15, 1951. (Box 46)
    - [Forword to] Know Your Library (7th edition). University of California, Los Angeles, 1951. (Box 46)
    - A Librarian on Leave. In Journal of the National Book League. [London], January 1951. (Box 46)
    - A Librarian takes Stock. In Antiquarian Booksellers' Association News Letter. [London], January 1951. (Box 46)
    - Multum in Parvo. In California Librarian, December 1951. (Box 46)
    - On the Poetry of Place. In Journal of the National Book League, June 1951. (Box 46)
    - A Rare Book Code. In Antiquarian Bookman, January 6, 1951. (Box 46)
    - [Editor] Rare Books and Research. Los Angeles: University of California Press, 1951. (Box 46)
    - Return to France. In Pacific Spectator, Summer 1951. (Box 46)
    - Sentimental Journey. [Reprinted from] California Librarian, September 1951. (Box 46)
  - 1952-1954
    - Bookshops and Cathedrals. In Hoja Volante, August 1952. (Box 47)
    - The College in My Life. In Occidental Alumnus, March 1952. (Box 47)
    - Essences of Britain. In ABA Annual, 1952. (Box 47)
    - The Folklore of Books. In Journal of the National Book League. [London], November 1952. (Box 47)
    - Homage to Browing. In California Librarian, December 1952. (Box 47)
    - In Praise of English Books. In Books of the Month. [London], October 1952. (Box 47)
    - [Foreword to] Know Your Library (8th edition). University of California, Los Angeles, 1952. (Box 47)
    - Land of Fiction..., 1952. (Box 47)
      (See box 24)
    - Librarian-on-Leave, Letters... to His Staff at UCLA... Los Angeles: [Printed at Los Angeles City College], 1952. (Box 47)
    - Manhattan Winter. In Hoja Volante, February 1952. (Box 47)
    - Manhattan Winter. In California Librarian, March 1952. (Box 47)
    - [Editor] Mercurius Redivivus; Being an Occasional News Letter from the William Andrews Clark Memorial Library (no.1), Autumn 1952. (Box 47)
    - Mid-Summer Miscellany. In California Librarian, September 1952. (Box 47)
    - On the Virtues of Smallness. In Hoja Volante, November 1952. (Box 47)
    - Once Upon a Time... In Antiquarian Bookman, August 2, 1952. (Box 47)
    - Transcontinental. In California Librarian, June 1952. (Box 47)
    - Two Small Books. In Hoja Volante, May 1952. (Box 47)
    - An American Library Reports. In Journal of the National Book League. [London], March-April 1953. (Box 47)
    - Books to Keep Me Warm. In Hoja Volante, February 1953. (Box 47)
    - Bookshops in the Los Angeles Area. In ALA Bulletin, June 1953. (Box 47)
    - Clark Collection of Oscar Wilde. In Campus Theater 170, UCLA, Program: An Ideal Husband, April 1953. (Box 47)
    - Essences of Britain. In PNLA Quarterly, January 1953. (Box 47)
    - Librarian Powell Takes to the Air. In Los Angeles Daily News, Christmas Book Section, December 7, 1953. (Box 47)
    - [Editor] Mercurius Redivivus; Being an Occasional News-letter from the William Andrews Clark Memorial Library (no.2), Spring 1953. (Box 47)
    - On Being up in the Air. In California Librarian, December 1953. (Box 47)
    - The Power to Evoke. [Reprinted from] Manuscripts, Summer 1953. (Box 47)
    - Some Writing About Los Angeles. In Los Angeles Times, November 12, 1953. (Box 47)
    - Stop Thief! A Nocturnal Episode in Library History. In Wilson Library Bulletin, December 1953. (Box 47)
    - This Dry and Wrinkled Land. In Arizona Librarian, July 1953. (Box 47)
    - This Dry and Wrinkled Land. In Hoja Volante, May and August 1953. (Box 47)
    - Land of Fiction; 32 novels and short stories about Southern California, from Ramona to the Loved One: a bibliographical essay. In California Librarian, June 1953. (Box 47)
    - This dry and wrinkled land. Arizona State Library Association, Phoenix, Arizona. Address delivered at the annual conference of the ASLA, Hacienda del Sol. Tucson, 1953. April 11, 1953. (Box 47)
    - Vroman's of Pasadena. Pasadena, California, Vroman's Bookstore, 1953. (Box 47)
    - Transcontinental. In Pi Lambda Theta Journal, Summer 1953. (Box 47)
    - [Editor] Acquisitions Policies and Interests of the UCLA Library. Occasional Papers no.1. UCLA Library, 1954. (Box 47)